chrisnguyen@zenonzeni.ca

Summary

Currently a 4th year honors student in information technology at York University & Tutoring at Code Ninjas on low to program and make software applications. My goal is to become a computer programmer that has worked on projects using Java or J2EE object-oriented programming, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), JavaScript (JSON, JQUERY, AJAX), SQL (MySQL, Oracle) for testing, implementing, and designed front-end web pages, websites, and applications. Another goal is educating kids, teens, and adults on computer technologies subjects.

WORK EXPERIENCE & RELATED EXPERIENCE

Coding Instructor & Curriculum Developer | June 2021 – Present

| 1 Year | Code Ninjas, Vogel Richmond Hill, Ontario

- In-person and virtually develop video games and teach ninjas how to make games, videos, robots.
- Teach how to make JavaScript games, Roblox games and Unity (C#) games.

Academic Peer Support Assistant | May 2020 – May

2022 | 2 Years | York University, Vaughan, Ontario

- Facilitate study session for students by analyzing, design, develop and test java programs.
- Students who took part of my study sessions do a whole grade letter better in the course.

Ride Operator | March 2018 - November 2019

2 Years | Canada Wonderland, Vaughan,

Ontario

- Participated in teams of more than ten and communicate with other associates to operate rides.
- We would follow best practices to meet ride performance goals and safety audits.

Web Developer | Volunteer | Indigenous Friends | Oct 2021 – Present

• Designing, developing, and deploying an AI Virtual Chat Bot using IBM Watson Assistant.

Personal and Academic Projects

Portfolio Website Project

Developed a website portfolio at https://zenonzeni.ca.

Web Camping Spot Reservation System (Prototype)

Developed a web-based information system at http://132.145.111.100/.

EDUCATION

Honors Bachelor Information Technology | 2018–2022 | GPA: B+|

York University, Vaughan, Ontario

Skills, Knowledge & Tools

Programming Languages, Frameworks, Technologies, and Data Format Knowledge.

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQUERY, AJAX, JSON, PHP, XML, XSL, Bootstrap, J2EE, and Java.

Database Languages

• SQL (MYSQL, and Oracle SQLPLUS)

Data Analytics Skills/Knowledge

• Classification, Regression, Basic Graphs/Statistics, and Data Cleaning using MATLAB or Python

System Administration/DevOps Skills

• Linux/Unix, MySQL, Oracle DB, IBM cloud tools, AWS, Oracle, Apache, Tomcat, Key Encryption, SSH, FTP, GitHub, and Git.

Tools/Knowledge

 Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook, MATLAB, Stata, Word, Zoom, (NetBeans, Eclipse Visual Studios, IntelliJ), etc.